A Guide to the Children's Home Society of Virginia Records, 1902-2008
Library of Virginia
- Series V. Photographs and posters, ca. 1903-ca. 2003. (Box 27-28 and two oversize folders (one in Oversize Box 64 and one in Oversize Cabinet 2, Drawer 12))
  Among the photographs are a large number of professional portraits, mostly of infants, many taken for use in the Home Finder. Also of interest are two posters, both created ca. 1903. One features photographs of the early leaders of the Children's Home Society, including John Garland Pollard and the Reverend William J. Maybee. It also lists the members of the Board of Directors, and gives a general overview of the services performed by the Society. The other features six sets of before-and-after photographs showing children "as received" and later, after spending some time in the care of the Society or being adopted. The photographs are accompanied by captions such as "homeless," "in a county poorhouse," and "beaten and abused by worthless parents" for the before pictures and "anchored," "now a daughter in a good home," and "two years training in family life" for the after shots.
  - Christmas photo shoots, ca. 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - CHS picnic, ca. 2003 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Early CHS photographs (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Foster mothers (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Memorial and donor plaques (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Oversize photographs (Box 64)
  - Portraits (Box 27, Folder 9-15)
  - Portraits by Arthur Clarke, 1950's-1960's (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
  - Portraits--staff and board members (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Posters (Oversize 2, Drawer 12)
  - Slides (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Snapshots (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
- Series VI. Clippings, 1920's-2000's. (Box 29-33)
  Newspaper and magazine clippings, some left loose and others kept in scrapbooks. A large portion of the clippings are brief items on topics including Children's Home Society fundraising campaigns and personnel changes on the staff or Board of Directors; other clippings concern associated organizations including Community Chest and United Way branches. There are also more lengthy feature stories on the Society and some of its clients. Of note is a collection of articles regarding a child named Andrew who was born in 1984, essentially without a brain, and placed by the CHS in an adoptive home. Other clippings focus on general issues in the field of adoption.
  - Clippings, 1920's-1970's (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1980's-2000's and undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Clippings re: baby born without a brain,1984-1989 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - VPA News-Clip Bureau clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1953 (Box 30)
  - Scrapbook, 1954-1959 (Box 31)
  - Scrapbook, 1960-1964 (Box 32)
  - Scrapbook, 1965-1966 (Box 33)
  - Scrapbook, 1970-1971 (Box 33)